Register of the William John Green Papers, 1911-1982
Hoover Institution Archives
William John Green Papers,
1911-1982
82090
Green, William John, 1892-
31 manuscript boxes (12.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Documenting the professional career of American agronomist William John Green, the papers consist of correspondence, speeches, reports, memoranda, minutes, newsletters, writings, and printed matter, relating to U.S. Farm Security Administration aid to tenant farmers, and to agricultural assistance to Guam, China, Peru, Burma, Bolivia, and Taiwan.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1982
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
U.S. Food Administration records, Hoover Institution Archives
O. J. (Oliver Julian) Todd papers, Hoover Institution Archives
United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration. China Office. Records, Hoover Institution Archives
Joint Commission on Rural Reconstruction in China (United States and China), miscellaneous records, Hoover Institution Archives
J. Franklin Ray papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical/Historical Note
August 19, 1892 Born, Ellsworth, Kansas
1916 Bachelor of Science in Agronomy, Oklahoma Agricultural and Mechanical College (A & M College)
1916 Appointed assistant in movable schools in the Oklahoma A & M College and U.S. Department of Agricultural Extension Service
1917 Assistant Boys Club agent in the Oklahoma Extension Service
1919 Superintendent of extension, Guam Agricultural Experiment Station, U.S. Department of Agriculture
1921 Extension agronomist in the Oklahoma A & M College
1922 Teacher of vocational agriculture in the Wakita High School, Wakita, Kansas
1926 County farm agent, Payne County, Oklahoma
1928 District farm agent, southeast quarter of Oklahoma
1931 M.S. agricultural economics, Oklahoma State University
1934 Senior administrative officer, Agricultural Adjustment Administration, Washington D.C.
1936 Assistant regional director of the Resettlement Administration and Farm Security Administration in Oklahoma and Texas
1944 Chief of the Field Staff and Coordination Section of the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA)
1945 Chief of the Agricultural Rehabilitation Division of the China Office of UNRRA
1948 Assistant Director of the U.S. Food Supply Mission to Peru
1950 Assistant economic commissioner and chief of the Agricultural Division of the U.S. Special Technical and Economic Mission to Burma
1953 Chief of the Agricultural and Natural Resources Field Party in Bolivia
1957-1962 Chief of the Agricultural Extension Division of the Joint Commission on Rural Reconstruction in Taiwan
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection documents the activities of noted American agronomist and chief administrative officer of the U.S. Department of Agriculture William John Green. The papers consist of correspondence, speeches, reports, memoranda, minutes, newsletters, and printed matter, relating to U.S. Farm Security Administration aid to tenant farmers, and to agricultural assistance to Guam, China, Peru, Burma, Bolivia, and Taiwan.
The papers include 35 years of "Hunger Fighters," published at irregular intervals in various parts of the world to keep former members of the Agricultural Rehabilitation Division of the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA) in touch with each other. In each series there are also "Bill's Letters," memoirs written as diaries about Green's experience and career in agriculture.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into six series: U.S. Department of Agriculture, Guam Agricultural Experiment Station files; U.S. Department of Agriculture, Farm Security Administration (FSA) files; Agricultural Rehabilitation Division of the China Office of United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA) files; U.S. Food Supply Mission in Peru files; U.S. Special Technical and Economic Mission to Burma files; Servicio Agricola Interamericano (SAI) in Bolivia files; and Joint Commission on Rural Reconstruction files (JCRR), Taipei, Taiwan, China.
Access Points
United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration.; United States. Farm Security Administration.; Agricultural assistance, American.; Agriculture--Bolivia.; Agriculture--Burma.; Agriculture--China.; Agriculture--Guam.; Agriculture--Peru.; Agriculture--Taiwan.; Agriculture--United States.; Bolivia.; Burma.; China.; Guam.; Peru.; Taiwan.; United States--Politics and government.; United States--Foreign relations.
Collection Contents
- U.S. Department of Agriculture, Guam Agricultural Experiment Station files, 1911-1923. (Box 1:)
  Includes reports, programs, instructions, printed matter, and writings.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Annual reports, 1911-1920 (Folder 1: 1)
    - "Farming in Guam," by William J. Green, 1919 (Folder 1: 2)
    - Annual Report of the Governor of Guam, 1919 (Folder 1: 3)
    - Fairs programs, and leaflets, 1920-1921 (Folder 1: 4)
    - Boys' and girls' agricultural clubs, program, instructions, and reports, 1920-1923 (Folder 1: 5-7)
      Includes Guam Club Member, nos. 1-7, 1920-1921
- U.S. Department of Agriculture files, Farm Security Administration (FSA), 1914-1954. (Box 1-13:)
  Contains programs, circulars, handbooks, manuals, instructions, polices, reports, memoranda, minutes, correspondence, printed matter, writings, clippings, and memoirs.
  - Cooperative extension work in agriculture and home economics, Oklahoma Agricultural and Mechanical College and U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1914-1939 (Folder 1: 8-12)
    Includes programs, reports, circulars, handbook, manual, and clippings of "Farm Notes by County Agent Green" from The Stillwater Democrat, The Cushing Daily Citizen, and The Oklahoma Extension News
  - Agricultural Adjustment Administration instructions and reports, 1934-1938 (Folder 1: 13-14)
  - Field workers conferences, programs, agenda, and minutes, 1934-1939 (Folder 2: 1-2)
  - Resettlement Administration program, reports, memoranda, and weekly conferences, 1934-1942 (Folder 2: 3-10)
  - "Tax Delinquency on Farm Real Estate in Texas," Texas Agricultural Experiment Station, 1935 (Folder 2: 11)
  - Committee on Plans for Future Drought Relief Program, 1936 (Folder 2: 12)
  - Disposal of canning equipment given to the Texas Rural Committee, 1936 (Folder 2: 13)
  - "Analyses of Basic Factors of Agricultural Labor in Texas and Oklahoma," report by the Labor Relations Division, circa 1936 (Folder 2: 14)
  - Farm Tenant Security Committee memoranda, polices, reports, and itineraries for field travel, 1936-1941 (Folder 2: 15-17)
  - Farm Tenant Security Committee memoranda, polices, reports, and itineraries for field travel, 1936-1941 (contd.) (Folder 3: 1)
  - Use of resettlement cameras, 1937 (Folder 3: 2)
  - Committee on Household Goods, 1937 (Folder 3: 3)
  - Land utilization project, 1937 (Folder 3: 4)
  - United States Congressman, W. R. Poage, correspondence, 1937 (Folder 3: 5)
  - Farm tenancy conference, Dallas, Texas, 1937 (Folder 3: 6)
  - Delegation of authority, 1937-1944 (Folder 3: 7-10)
  - "A Brief Informatory Statement of Agriculture in Texas,", circa 1938 (Folder 3: 11)
  - "Bankhead-Jones Farm Tenant Statistical Data,", 1938-1939 (Folder 3: 12-13)
  - Land Use Planning Committee, 1938-1941 (Folder 3: 14)
  - Migratory farm workers camps program and reports, 1938-1942 (Folder 3: 15-17)
  - Legal opinion, 1938-1943 (Folder 3: 18-19)
  - National Resources Planning Board reports, pamphlets, and memoranda, 1938-1943 (Folder 4: 1-4)
  - Tenant purchase (TP) instruction letters, conferences, meetings, and reports, 1938-1944 (Folder 4: 5-12)
  - Food production amond low-income farm families, 1938-1944 (Folder 5: 1-3)
    Includes newsletters, memoranda, reports, and brochures
  - "What the FSA Is Doing in Texas," speech by W. J. Green at the State Fair of Texas, Dallas, October 19, 1939 (Folder 5: 4)
  - "Annual Agricultural Conference for Southwestern States: Proceedings,", 1939 (Folder 5: 5)
  - "Speakers' Guide and Reference," by Information Division, circa 1939 (Folder 5: 6)
  - State Land Use Planning Office's reports, 1939-1940 (Folder 5: 7)
  - "Memorandum for the Administrator,", 1939-1941 (Folder 5: 8-9)
  - Loans and collection reports, 1939-1941 (Folder 5: 10-12)
  - Program Analyses and Research Advisory Committee, 1939-1942 (Folder 5: 13)
  - Training schools for TP committeemen, program outline, schedule for meetings and discussions, tenants agreement form, 1939-1943 (Folder 6: 1-4)
  - Personnel action authorized by W. J. Green as acting regional director, 1939-1943 (Folder 6: 5)
  - District engineer's bulletins and reports, 1939-1944 (Folder 6: 6-8)
  - District and region meetings and progress reports, 1939-1947 (Folder 6: 9-14)
  - District and region meetings and progress reports, 1939-1947 (Contd.) (Folder 7: 1-2)
  - "Report of the Proceedings of the Open Meeting of Farm Tenancy Hearing," Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, 1940 (Folder 7: 3)
  - An Outline of the Water Facilities Program, Soil Conservation Service, circa 1940 (Folder 7: 4)
  - "Farm Debt Adjustment and Improved Tenure Manual,", 1940 (Folder 7: 5)
  - State Meetings Committee, 1940 (Folder 7: 6-7)
  - State Negro Sub Committee minutes, 1940 (Folder 7: 8)
  - State Advisory Committee meetings minutes, 1940-1941 (Folder 7: 9-12)
  - National defense and agriculture memoranda, 1940-1941 (Folder 7: 13)
  - Investigation reports, 1940-1941 (Folder 7: 14-15)
  - TP insurance, 1940-1941 (Folder 7: 16)
  - Cooperative Division letters and brochures, 1940-1942 (Folder 8: 1)
  - Loans to low income farmers for purchase of Oklahoma school land, 1940-1942 (Folder 8: 2-4)
  - Farm appraisal, 1940-1942 (Folder 8: 5)
  - Water Facilities Procedure Manual, 1940 and 1942 (Folder 8: 6)
  - Water Facilities Area Planning Handbook, 1941 (Folder 8: 7)
  - "Food for Freedom," bulletin, 1941 (Folder 8: 8)
  - Social Security Board, 1941 (Folder 8: 9)
  - "Induction Training Course,", 1941 (Folder 8: 10)
  - "Some Facts on the TP Program for 1941" (Folder 8: 11)
  - Material for broadcast, 1941 (Folder 8: 12)
  - Delinquent TP accounts, 1941 (Folder 8: 13)
  - "Report of the Proceedings of the Open Meeting of Farm Tenancy Hearing," by C. M. Evans, regional director, FSA chairman, 1941 (Folder 8: 14)
  - "Wheeler-Case Irrigation Program," report on conference, 1941 (Folder 8: 15)
  - Inter-regional conference reports, 1941 (Folder 8: 16)
  - Borrower's narrative work sheet, 1941 (Folder 8: 17)
  - Annual TP conference journal of proceedings, 1941 (Folder 8: 18)
  - "Points Receiving Special Emphasis in the 1941 Program of the Farm Security Administration," memo (Folder 9: 1)
  - Appraisal bulletin, 1941-1942 (Folder 9: 2)
  - Farm Home improvement program, 1941-1942 (Folder 9: 3)
  - Weekly conference reports, 1941-1942 (Folder 9: 4)
  - Problem Area Working Committee, 1941-1942 (Folder 9: 5-6)
  - Southern Great Plains Council correspondence, memoranda, and minutes, 1941-1942 (Folder 9: 7-9)
  - Construction, repairs, and improvements, 1941-1943 (Folder 9: 10)
  - "To Members of County FSA Advisory Councils and Committees," instructions and handbooks, 1941-1943 (Folder 9: 11-15)
  - "To Members of County FSA Advisory Councils and Committees," instructions and handbooks, 1941-1943 (Contd.) (Folder 10: 1-3)
  - South Central Region Post-war Planning committee, 1941-1943 (Folder 10: 4-8)
  - Administrators' staff conferences reports, 1941-1944 (Folder 10: 9-15)
  - Administrators' staff conferences reports, 1941-1944 (Folder 11: 1-2)
  - Farm and home expenses reports, 1942 (Folder 11: 3)
  - Post-war Planning Committee memoranda, 1942 (Folder 11: 4)
  - War Production Board's conservation orders, 1942 (Folder 11: 5)
  - Regional tenure study, 1942 (Folder 11: 6)
  - Efficiency Rating Committee, 1942 (Folder 11: 7)
  - Heavy Equipment Committee, circa 1942 (Folder 11: 8)
  - Denton County, Texas reports, 1942 (Folder 11: 9)
  - "The Area Specialist and His Part in Farm Ownership Programs,", 1942 (Folder 11: 10)
  - Regional Coordinating Committee, 1942 (Folder 11: 11)
  - War Department and government agencies conference minutes, Dallas, Texas, 1942 (Folder 11: 12)
  - "Appraisal of Annual Meeting of Farm Ownership (FO) Borrowers," reports, 1942-1943 (Folder 11: 13)
  - Transfer of project farms to FO division, correspondence and polices, 1942-1943 (Folder 11: 14-15)
  - FO division staff letters, 1942-1944 (Folder 11: 16)
  - Inter-Bureau Committee on post-war programs, 1942-1944 (Folder 11: 17-18)
  - Oklahoma Lake West Subdivision, 1943 (Folder 11: 19)
  - "Area Delineation and Description, South Central Region,", 1943 (Folder 11: 20-21)
    Includes map
  - "FO Handbook,", 1943 (Folder 11: 22)
  - "Agricultural Department Appropriation Bill for 1944,", May 21, 1943 (Folder 12: 1)
  - Allocation of FO funds by counties, 1943 (Folder 12: 2-3)
  - "Notes on Tenure Phase of Post-War Programs,", 1943 (Folder 12: 4)
  - "Suggestions for Planning Post-War Agriculture in Oklahoma,", 1943 (Folder 12: 5)
  - "Neighborhood Discussion Groups among Low-income Farm Families in Texas," by T. Wilson Longmore, Assistant Social Science Analyst, Arkansas, 1943 (Folder 12: 6)
  - Field trips reports, 1943-1944 (Folder 12: 7)
  - "Through the Depression Years" talks and papers, 1934-1940, by William J. Green, 1944 (Folder 12: 8)
  - "Through the War Years, 1941-1944" talks and papers given mostly as Assistant Regional Director of the Farm Security Administration, later to become the "Farmers Home Administration, Region VIII," by William J. Green, circa 1945 (Folder 12: 9)
  - Farmer's Home Administration instructions, 1947-1955 (Folder 13: 1-2)
  - "Acts of Confress Administered by the Farmders Home Administration,", 1954 (Folder 13: 3)
- Agricultural Rehabilitation Division of the China Office of United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA) files, 1934-1982 (Box 13-22:)
  Includes reports, supply analyses, programs, memoranda, correspondence, printed matter, writings, clippings, maps, and memoirs
  - Agricultural rehabilitation in the Yellow River flooded areas, correspondence, reports, supply analyses, and clippings, 1934-1947 (Folder 13: 4-10)
  - Agricultural rehabilitation in the Yellow River flooded areas, correspondence, reports, supply analyses, and clippings, 1934-1947 (contd.) (Folder 14: 1-6)
  - Geography of Soils of China, by James Thorp, 1936 (Folder 14: 7)
  - Food situation in China reports, 1937-1946 (Folder 15: 1)
  - Annual progress and program reports, 1943-1947 (Folder 15: 2-3)
  - "Program and Estimated Requirements for Relief and Rehabilitation in China by the Government of the Republic of China,", 10 September 1944 (Folder 15: 4)
  - Flood control, correspondence and reports, 1944-1947 (Folder 15: 5)
  - "Veterinary Report on China," by C. S. M. Hopkirk, circa 1945 (Folder 15: 6)
  - "Agriculture in Manchuria," report by the historical section of UNRRA, circa 1945 (Folder 15: 7)
  - "Structure and Work of Chinese Government Agricultural Agencies," by Pao-chuan Chao, director, Rural Economic Department, Ministry of Agriculture and Forestry, circa 1945 (Folder 15: 8)
  - "Proposed Program of Agricultural Development in China," by P.W. Tsou, 1945 (Folder 15: 9)
  - U.S. Army cooperation, memo and orders, 1945 (Folder 15: 10)
  - Agricultural resources in China reports by region, 1945-1946 (Folder 15: 11-13)
  - Food production in liberated areas in Kweichow and Kwangsi provinces, 1945-1946 (Folder 15: 14)
  - Agricultural conditions in China reports, 1945-1947 (Folder 15: 15-16)
  - Condensed weekly reports, 1945-1947 (Folder 16: 1-4)
  - Operational analyses reports, 1945-1947 (Folder 16: 5-7)
  - Weekly staff conference reports, 1945-1947 (Folder 16: 8-12)
  - Conversion Tables for Weights and Measures in U.S., British and Chinese Metric Systems, 1946 (Folder 17: 1)
  - "Agricultural Recourses of China," by Tsung-han Shen, Acting Director, National Agricultural Research Bureau, 1946 (Folder 17: 2)
  - "Report of Colonel R. L. Harrison, Dr. K. Stuart Hetzel and Dr. David H. Bau on Food Deficit Areas in China,", 1946 (Folder 17: 3)
  - "Report of the Regional Agricultural Rehabilitation Officers' Conference,", 1946 (Folder 17: 4)
  - Headquarters office, programs and reports, 1946 (Folder 17: 5)
  - Plant Disease and Insect Control Program, circa 1946 (Folder 17: 6)
  - Chinese National Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (CNRRA): Its purpose, Functions and Organization, Department of Public Relations, CNRRA, Shanghai, 1946 (Folder 17: 7)
  - "The Agricultural Analyst's Digest,", 1946-1947 (Folder 17: 8-12)
  - Edwin R. Henson, Director of Agricultural Rehabilitation Division, UNRRA correspondence, 1946-1947 (Folder 17: 13)
  - Work in Communist-held areas, reports, memoranda, and correspondence, 1946-1947 (Folder 17: 14-15)
  - Personnel and office staffing authorization, recommendations, and trusteeship candidates, 1946-1948 (Folder 18: 1-3)
  - "History of Agricultural Rehabilitation Work in China," by W. J Green, 1947 (Folder 18: 4)
    Includes research materials
  - "Agricultural Rehabilitation in China," operational analysis report, 1947 (Folder 18: 5)
  - Approved projects memoranda, reports, and map, 1947 (Folder 18: 6-7)
  - Agricultural Industries Service (AIS) report, 1947 (Folder 18: 8)
  - Home demonstration work proposals, 1947 (Folder 18: 9)
  - Agricultural rehabilitation in Taiwan (Formosa), 1947 (Folder 18: 10)
  - Information for supply conference, 1947 (Folder 18: 11)
  - Livestock introdution, 1947 (Folder 18: 12)
  - History of fishery progress, 1947 (Folder 18: 13)
  - Farm machinery program, 1947 (Folder 18: 14)
  - Information on the Agricultural Rehabilitation Program for the Wedemeyer Mission, 1947 (Folder 19: 1)
  - "Water and Land Problems in China," by C. P. Christopoulos, 1947 (Folder 19: 2)
  - "Report on Studies on the Yangtze River Flood Prevention Project," by Ir. J. Ringers, UNRRA Conservancy Engineer, 1947 (Folder 19: 3)
  - "The Christian Message to the Chinese Farmer," by Chang Fu-Liang, 1947 (Folder 19: 4)
  - Regional Agricultural Rehabilitation Project. Reports for Chekiang and Kwangsi regions, 1947 (Folder 19: 5)
  - Division of Supply Coordination reports, 1947 (Folder 19: 6)
  - "Monograph on the Grand Canal Project," by W. J. Van Der Oord, UNRRA conservancy engineer, 1947 (Folder 19: 7)
  - Ecological Crop Geography of China and Its Agro-Climatic Analogues in North America, by M. Y. Nuttonson, 1947 (Folder 19: 8)
  - "Mongolian Relief Program, China Relief Mission," by Don Warner, 1947 (Folder 19: 9)
  - Hunger Fighters, nos. 1-20, 1947-1952 (Folder 19: 10-15)
  - Hunger Fighters, nos. 21-50, 1953-1964 (Folder 20: 1-11)
  - Hunger Fighters, nos. 51-79, 1965-1979 (Folder 21: 1-10)
  - Hunger Fighters, nos. 80-85, 1980-1982 (Folder 22: 1-2)
  - Post-war agricultural reconstruction plans, 1947-1948 (Folder 22: 3)
  - Allocation and distribution of fertilizer, reports and memoranda, 1947-1948 (Folder 22: 4)
  - Committee for the Council for the Far East, 1947-1948 (Folder 22: 5-7)
  - Extension work program, memoranda, correspondence, and conference report, 1947-1948 (Folder 22: 8)
  - Agreements between UNRRA and the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, 1948 (Folder 22: 9)
  - "Proposed Program of Agricultural Extension for China for the Year 1948" (Folder 22: 10)
  - "Bill's China Letters, 1945-1948," by William J. Green, circa 1952 (Folder 22: 11)
  - Pao-Hsu Ho, 1895-1963, by Gertrude C. Ho, circa 1970 (Folder 22: 12)
- U.S Food Supply Mission in Peru files, 1948-1950 (Box 23:)
  Consists of programs, reports, printed matter, writings, and clippings
  Arranged chronologically
  - "Posibilidades para el desarrollo agricola a lo largo de los Rios Alto Ucayali y Pachitea," Ministerio de Agricultura, Lima, Peru, 1949 (Folder 23: 1)
  - "Estudio economico del bonito," Lima, Peru, "U.S. Tractors in Peru Plow Furrows to Future," by the Latin American editor of The Christian Science Monitor, Peruvian Times; 1949 (Folder 23: 2-3)
  - "El programa norte americano del 'Cuarto Punto'" Excelsior, 1949 (Folder 23: 4)
  - Informaciones del SCIPA, Ministerio de Agricultura,, Lima, Peru, nos. 16-18, 1949 (Folder 23: 5)
  - Monthly progress reports, 1949-1950 (Folder 23: 6-7)
  - Agricultural Progress in Peru: Summary Report, 1943-1949, 1950 (Folder 23: 8)
  - Clippings from The Daily Oklahoma, 1950 (Folder 23: 9)
  - "Progress of the Institute of Inter-American Affairs-Point IV in Action," by Kenneth R. Iverson, president, Institute of Inter-American Affairs, Foreign Commerce Weekly, 1951 (Folder 23: 10)
  - "Bill's Latin-American Letters, Series I, 1948-1950," by William J. Green (Folder 23: 11)
- U.S. Special Technical and Economic Mission to Burma, 1949-1953 (Box 23-24:)
  Includes programs, memoranda, reports, writings, correspondence, clippings and press releases.
  - "The Quest for Individual Autonomy in Burmese Personality with Particular Reference to the Arakan," by L. M. Hanks, 1949 (Folder 23: 12)
  - William J. Green's assignment to Burma as agricultural officer, press release, Office of Information, Economic Cooperation Administration, September 15, 1950 (Folder 23: 13)
  - "The Agriculture of Burma," by the Office of Foreign Agricultural Relations of the U.S. Department of Agriculture, August 1950 (Folder 23: 14)
  - "Background Information for Burma," based on the "Check List of Basic Information" sent by Dr. C. W. Chang, as revised by Sir Bernard Binns, 1950 (Folder 23: 15)
  - "Union of Burma Agricultural and Rural Development Five Years Plan,", circa 1950 (Folder 23: 16)
  - Fishery industry in Burma, 1950 (Folder 23: 17)
  - Trip to Kachin State, report by Orland E. White, 1950 (Folder 23: 18)
  - Agriculture Division monthly reports, 1950-1952 (Folder 23: 19-20)
  - "Agricultural Research Program for Burma," by W. W. Burr, agricultural research advisor, 1951 (Folder 24: 1)
  - Rice Milling Project reports, 1951 (Folder 24: 2)
  - An Economic Classification of Land in Burma, by J. T. Sanders, consultant and U Ba Tin, assistant director of agriculture, government of the Union of Burma, 1951 (Folder 24: 3)
  - Correspondence, 1951 (Folder 24: 4)
  - Burma rural youth leaders in the United States, clippings and press releases, 1951 (Folder 24: 5)
  - Personnel of the Ministry of Agriculture and Forests of Burma, 1951 (Folder 24: 6)
  - "Agricultural Research,", 1951 (Folder 24: 7)
  - Cotton seed project, 1951 (Folder 24: 8)
  - Economic Cooperation Administration (ECA) in the Union of Burma, 1951 (Folder 24: 9)
  - Technical assistance personnel, memoranda and correspondence, 1951 (Folder 24: 10)
  - "Soil Conservation in the Shan States,", 1951 (Folder 24: 11)
  - "Economic Survey of Burma,", 1951-1952 (Folder 24: 12)
  - Otto K. Hunerwadel, Agricultural Adviser to the Shan State reports, clippings, and memorial services program, 1951-1952 (Folder 24: 13)
  - "An Economic Appraisal of Burma and ECA Program for 1951-52" (Folder 24: 14)